Finding Aid for Lawrence C. Patrick Jr. papers, 1987-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lawrence C. Patrick Jr. papers 1987-2009
Patrick, Lawrence C.
0.7 linear feet
2010053 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Lawrence C. Patrick, Jr. (donor no. 10265 ) in 2010.
Periodic additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Lawrence C. Patrick Jr. is a Detroit attorney. From 1989 to 1995, he was member and president of the Detroit Board of Education. Elected as an educational reformer, while in office, Patrick was active in his support of local school control through empowerment agreements, charters, and other related management options.
The Lawrence C. Patrick, Jr. collection consists of files relating to his involvement in Group of Organized Detroiters for Quality Education (GOOD), 1987-1989, his campaign to the Detroit Board of Education in 1988, and his efforts to implement reforms and school empowerment through local control of budget, personnel, curriculum, etc. There are also speeches, clippings, and collected reports and studies relating to issues within the Detroit Public School system.
Subjects:
Charter schools--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.). Board of Education.; Educational change--Michigan--Detroit.; Patrick, Lawrence C.; Schools--Michigan--Detroit.
- Education files
  - Clippings and informational material (Box 1)
  - Group of Organized Detroiters (GOOD) for Quality Education
    - 1987 (Box 1)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Detroit School Board election, 1988
    - Support of Church of God in Christ clergy (Box 1)
    - HOPE candidates (Hayden, Olmstead and Patrick for Education), 1988-1991 (Box 1)
    - Letters of congratulations and miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Board of Education tenure
    - Arthur Jefferson, 1989 (Box 1)
      (discussion of contract and transition)
    - White Conference on Choice in Education, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Detroit Male Academy, ca. 1990 (Box 1)
    - Chartered schools, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Public School Academies (policy statements) (Box 1)
    - Republican Party Platform Committee appearance, 1992 (Box 1)
    - National Education Association conference, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Other materials
    - Various issues, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Detroit Reform School Board, 1999 (Box 1)
    - School Improvement Plan (David Adamany), 1999, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Detroit Public Schools Chief Executive Officer campaign, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - School Equity Caucus, school funding studies, 2004 (Box 1)
    - New Schools Initiative, 2009 (Box 1)